Mets senator from the state of Illinois
Barack Obama
Thank you so much
Thank you thank you so much
Thank you so much thank you thank you
Thank you Dick Durbin
You make us all proud
I'll be home
Of the great state of Illinois
Crossroads of the nation
Land of Lincoln
Let me express my deepest gratitude
For the privilege of addressing this convention
Tonight is a particular honor for me because let's face
My presence on this stage
Is pretty unlikely
My father was a foreign student
Born and raised
In a small village
We grew up herding goats
Went to school in a tin roof Shack
His father
My grandfather
Weather cook
A domestic servant to the British
But my grandfather had larger dreams
Sprint son
Work
And perseverance
My father got a scholarship to
Study in a magical place
America
That Shone as a beacon of freedom and opportunity
Just so many who have come before
Not studying here
My father met my mother
She was born in a town on the other side of the world
Intense
Her father worked on oil rigs
And Farms through most of the depression
The day after Pearl Harbor
My grandfather
Signed up
Purdue
John Patton's Army marched across Europe
Back home my grandmother
Raise the baby and went to work
On a bomber assembly line
After the war they studied on the GI Bill
Bought a house through FHA
And later moved West
All the way to Hawaii in search of opportunity
M82 had Big Dreams for their daughter
A common dream born of two continents
My parents shared not only an improbable love
They shared an Abiding Faith in the possibilities of this nation
It would give me an African name
Or blessed
Believing that in a tolerant America
Your name is no barrier to success
They imagine they imagine me going to the best school
Eminem even though they weren't Rich because in a generous America you don't have to be rich
Achieve your potential
They're both passed away.
And yet I know that on this night
They don't look down
On me with great pride
They stayed here
And I stand here today
Grateful for the diversity of my heritage
Aware that my parents Dreams live on in my two precious daughters
I stand here knowing
The my story is part of the larger American story that
I owe a debt to all of those who came before me and that in no other country on Earth
Is my story even possible
Tonight
We Gather to affirm
The greatness of our nation
Not because of the height of are skyscrapers or the power of our military or the size of our economy
Our pride is based on a very simple plan
Summed up in a declaration made over 200 years ago
We hold these truths
All men are created
That they are endowed by their creator with certain inalienable right
That among these are life
Liberty and the pursuit of happiness
Is the true genius
Of America
A fade effect and simple drinks
Unassisted on small miracle
That we can talk in our children at night
And know that they are fed and clothed and safe from harm
So we can say what we think right what we think without hearing a sudden knock on the door
That we can have an idea and start own business
Without paying a price
That we can participate in the political process
Without fear of Retribution
M&R boats will be counted
At least most of the time
This year in this election
We are called
To reaffirm our values and our commitments to hold them against
A hard reality
MC Hammer Measuring Up
The legacy of our forbears
And a promise of future Generations
And fellow Americans
Democrats
Republicans
Independence I say to you tonight
We have more work to do
More work to do
For the workers that made in Galesburg Illinois
We're losing their union jobs at the Maytag plant that's moving to Mexico
And now we're having to compete with their own children
4 jobs that pay 7 Bucks an hour
More to do for the father that I met who was losing his job and choking back the tears wondering how he would pay for
$4,500 a month
For the drugs and Sun needs
The health benefits to be counted on
More to do for the young woman in East st. Louis
And thousands more like her
Where's the graves
Have the drive has the will but doesn't have the money
To go to college
Now don't get me wrong
The people I meet in small towns and big cities and diners
And office parks
They don't expect government to solve all their problems
They know they have to work hard to get ahead
And they want to
Going to the collar counties around Chicago and people will tell you they don't want their tax money Wasted by welfare agency
The Pentagon
Go and go into any inner city neighborhood
And folks will tell you
The government alone
Did teach our kids to learn
They know the parents have to teach
The children can achieve unless we raise their
And turn off the television sets and eradicate the slander that says a black youth with a book is that
I know those things
People don't expect people don't expect government to solve all their problems
But they sent
Deep in their bones
It would just a slight change in priorities we can make sure that every child in America has a decent shot at like
And if the doors of opportunity remain open to all
They know we can do better
Me want that choice
In this election
We offer that choice
Our party has chosen a man to lead us
Who embodies the best
This country has to offer and that man is John Kerry
John Kerry understands the ideals of community
Faith and service because they defined as life
From his heroic service to Vietnam to his years of the prosecutor and lieutenant governor
Through two decades in the United States Senate
He's devoted himself
Today's country
Again and again we seem to make tough choices when easier ones were available his values
And his record
Affirm what is best enough
John Kerry believes in America where hard work is rewarded
Sunset of offering tax breaks
The company shipping jobs overseas
Shoppers
Lumber companies creating jobs here at home
John Kerry believe in America
We're all Americans can afford the same health coverage our politicians in Washington have for themselves
John Terry
Believe in energy Independence
So we aren't held hostage to the profits of oil companies or the sabotage for an oil field
John Kerry believes in the Constitutional freedoms
That made our country the Envy of the world
And he will never sacrifice our basic liberties
North Face
As a wedge to divide
And John Kerry believe
Vet in a dangerous world
War must be an option sometimes but it should never be
The first stop
You know
A while back
A while back I got a young man named Seamus
VFW Hall in East Moline Illinois
He was a good-looking kid 6263 clear ride with an easy smile
He told me he joined the Marines
I was heading to work the following week
And as I listened to him explain
Why he didn't list
The absolute Faith he had in our country and its leaders
His Devotion to duty and service I thought
This young man was all that any of us might
Ever hope for in a trap
But then I ask myself
Are we serving
Seamus as well as he's serving us
I thought of the 900
Men and women
Sons and Daughters husbands and wives
Friends and Neighbors
Who won't be returning to their own hometowns
I thought of the family as I've met who were struggling to get by without a loved one's full income
Whose loved ones have returned with a luminous
Order of shatter
But still
Black long-term health benefits
Because they were reservists
When we send our young men and women into Harm's Way
We have a solemn obligation
Not to fudge the numbers or save the truth about why they are going to care for their families while they're gone
10 to the soldiers upon their return at the never ever go to war without enough troops
Who won the war secure the peace and earned the respect of the world
Now let me be clear
Let me be clear
We have real enemies in the world
These enemies must be found
They must be pursued
And they must be defeated
John Kerry knows this
And just as lieutenant
Jerry did not hesitate to risk his life to protect the men
Who served with him in Vietnam President Carrie will not hesitate one moment
To use our military might to keep America safe and secure
John Terry believe
In America
Eddie knows that it's not enough
For just some of us
Alongside our famous individualism
There's another ingredient
In the American Saga
A belief that we're all connected as one piece
If there's a child on the southside of Chicago who can't read
That matters to me even if
If there's a senior citizen somewhere who can't pay for the prescription drugs and having to choose between medicine in the rent
Summit 4x4 even if it's not my grandparents
If there's an Arab American family being rounded up
Without benefit of an attorney or due process that threatens my civil liberties
Videos of fundamental beliefs
It is a fundamental belief I am My Brother's Keeper
I am My Sister's Keeper that makes this country work
That's what allows us to pursue our individual dreams
And yet still come together as one American family
E pluribus unum
Out of many
One
Now even as we speak
There are those who are preparing
The Divide
The Spin Master
The negative ad Peddlers
Embrace the politics
Anything Goes
Well
I say to them tonight
There is not a liberal America and a conservative America there is the United States
Of America there is not a Black America and a white America
Latino America and Asian America United States of America
Indian
Indian Indian that's what this election is about
Do we participate
Enter politics of cynicism
Or do we participate in a politics of Hope
John Kerry calls on us to Hope
John Edwards calls on us to Hope
I'm not talking about blind optimism here
The almost willful ignorance
The things unemployment will go away if we just don't think about it
Or Healthcare crisis will solve itself if we just ignore it that's not what I'm talking about I'm talking about
Something more substantial
The hope of slaves sitting around a fire singing freedom
The hope of immigrants setting out for dip
Distant Shores
The hope of a young Naval lieutenant
Bravely patrolling the Mekong Delta
The hope of a mill worker son
Who dares to defy the odds
The hope of a skinny kid with a funny name who believes that America has a place for him too
Who helped in the face of difficulty
Hope in the face of uncertainty The Audacity Of Hope
What is God's greatest gift to us
The Bedrock of this nation
I believe
In Things Not Seen
I believe that there better days ahead
I believe that we can give our middle class
Relief and provide Working Families with a road opportunity
I believe we can provide jobs for the jobless
Homes for the homeless and reclaim young people in cities Across America from violence and despair
I believe
We have a right to swing their backs and as we stand on the crossroads of History
We can make the right choices
And meet the challenges that face us
America tonight if you feel the same energy that I do if you feel the same urgency that I
If you feel the same passion that I do if you feel the same hopefulness that I do if we do what
We must through that I have no doubt
But all across the country from Florida to Oregon from
Washington to Maine the people will rise up in November and John Terry will be sworn in as
The president and John Edwards will be sworn in as vice-president
And this country will reclaim its promise
And all of this long political Darkness
A Brighter Day Will Come
Thank you very much everybody God bless you